Almas Baimagambetov

STATEMENT

I am a Lecturer in Game Development at the University of Brighton, where I teach a range of computer science, software and game development modules. My research is in the field of data visualization. I am the author and maintainer of FXGL, a game engine used by multiple academic institutions to teach game development. I contribute to a number of open-source projects on GitHub and run an educational YouTube channel covering game and software development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

| Sept. 2018 - Present | Lecturer in Game Development University of Brighton, UK |
|---|--|
| | University of Brighton, UK |
| Oct 2017 Aug 2019 | Don't time I actumen in Come Development |
| Oct. 2017 - Aug. 2018 | Part-time Lecturer in Game Development |
| | Part-time Lecturer in Game Development University of Brighton, UK |
| , | |
| Oct. 2015 - Oct. 2017 | Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Game Development |
| 0 | Hourly-Paid Lecturer in Game Development University of Brighton, UK |
| | Chiversity of Drighton, CA |
| I 2019 O . 2016 | |
| Jan 2013 - Oct. 2016 | In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) |
| | In-house Programmer (Zero-Hour Contract) LLP AktubNIGRI, Kazakhstan |
| | , , |
| Oct. 2012 - Feb. 2015 | Guest Speaker and Mentor for IT students (Volunteer) |
| 300. 2012 100. 2019 | Dill 1 Cil III |
| | Bellerbys College, UK |

EDUCATION

| July 2015 - April 2020 | PhD in Computer Science, University of Brighton, UK | |
|------------------------|--|--|
| (Expected) | Thesis: Automated visualization of grouped networks | |
| | using Euler diagrams and graphs | |
| | keywords: set theory, graph theory, topology, | |
| | computational geometry & graphics | |
| | | |
| Oct.2012 - July 2015 | BSc Computer Science (Games), University of Brighton, UK | |
| | Final year project: | |
| | Analysis of software development issues in large scale games | |
| | Project grade: 87% (A+), Degree: 1st Class Honours | |
| | | |
| Sept. 2011 - June 2012 | Foundation Degree in IT, Bellerbys College, UK | |
| | Grade: 94 % (A +) | |

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Advanced: Java, JavaFX, Kotlin,

game engine development (ECS, AI, UI, IO, serialization,

physics, event systems, networking, scripting), API design, TDD, FDD, DDD, CI, deployment, software development principles and practices,

algorithms and data structures

Intermediate: C++, JS, SDL2, OpenGL, Git, Win/Mac/Linux, Agile, LAT_EX Beginner: Unity, SQL, HTML, CSS, Haskell, Python, Node.js, Spring

Interests and Activities

game development, software development, computer science data visualization, automated graphical layout generation education, technology, open-source, chess

Languages

English: Fluent / Professional

Kazakh: Native Russian: Native

Awards

| June 2019 | Post Student Dar | oer, Diagrams 2018 | Conforma |
|-----------|--------------------|--------------------|--------------|
| June zurs | - Best Student Pai | ber. Diagrams zura | S Conterence |

Sept. 2015 International Research Scholarship (50% fee reduction)

University of Brighton

July 2015 Best Final Year Development Project (£250)

The FDM Group Prize

Nov. 2014 Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000)

University of Brighton

Nov. 2013 Academic Merit Based Scholarship (£1000)

University of Brighton

June 2012 Top #1 Foundation Student, Bellerbys College

May 2012 Best IT Student, Bellerbys College

RESEARCH AND PROFESSIONAL TALKS

| June 2019 | Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks Using Euler Diagrams and Graphs (CEM Conference) |
|------------|---|
| April 2019 | Java and JavaFX Game Development (Brighton Java Meetup) |
| June 2018 | Generating Effective Euler Diagrams (10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams) |
| May 2017 | Novel Algorithm for Euler Diagram Generation (University of Brighton Internal Conference) |
| March 2017 | Data Visualization Workshop (Presenter at Data Visualization Brighton Meetup) |
| Feb. 2017 | An Inductive Approach to P-preserving Euler Diagram Generation (Visual Modelling Group Talk) |
| June 2016 | Grouped Networks and Associated Challenges (University of Brighton Internal Conference) |
| May 2016 | Euler Diagram Generation Techniques (Visual Modelling Group Talk) |

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Stapleton, G., Howse, J. and Blake, A. (2020) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 11th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Tallinn, 24-28 August 2020. (submitted long paper).
- 2. **Baimagambetov, A.**, Howse, J., Stapleton, G. and Delaney, A. (2018) Generating Effective Euler Diagrams In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (long paper).
- 3. **Baimagambetov, A.** (2018) Automated Visualization of Grouped Networks In: 10th International Conference on the Theory and Application of Diagrams, Edinburgh, 18-22 June 2018. (Graduate Symposium report).